smashballoon.com 2018-08-27

# Privacy Policy

This page outlines what personal data is collected on our website, how it is stored, whether it is transferred to third-parties, and how to request deletion of this data.

### Support and Contact Forms

When you submit a request through any of the contact or support forms on our website we ask for your name and email address in order to be able to respond to your request. This information, along with your public IP address, is stored as a form entry in our database. The request and your information is also forwarded to our support ticketing helpdesk, powered by [Freshdesk](https://freshdesk.com/) ([privacy policy](https://www.freshworks.com/privacy/)).

### Third Party Widgets

We make use of certain third-party widgets on our website in order to enhance the experience, namely; YouTube video embeds and social media widgets/buttons.

These widgets may collect your IP address, your web browser User Agent, store and retrieve cookies on your browser, embed additional tracking, and monitor your interaction with the widget, including correlating your social media account with whatever action you take within the widget, if you are logged in to that network. For more information about how this data may be used, please see the associated data privacy policy below:

YouTube: <https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/7671399?p=privacy_guidelines>  
Facebook: <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/update>  
Twitter: <https://twitter.com/en/privacy#update>  
LinkedIn: <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy>  
Google: [https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en&gl=us](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en&gl=us)

### Third Party Resources

Our website makes use of several third-party resources for both functional and performance reasons. Requests to load these resources may make your IP address visible to the associated resource, who may use it in accordance with their data privacy policy.  The third party resources are listed below:

Stripe is a payment processor which allows you to securely and conveniently checkout while purchasing a product on our website. We utilize their scripts to integrate the payment process into our website. Stripe’s privacy policy can be found here: <https://stripe.com/us/privacy>

Gravatar is used to display avatar images of people whose product reviews are displayed on our website. Privacy policy: <https://automattic.com/privacy/>

MaxCDN is a Content Delivery Network which we use to serve certain static files on our website in order to improve performance. These requests make your IP address visible to MaxCDN, who may use it in accordance with their data privacy policy: <https://www.maxcdn.com/legal/#pp>

### Our Plugin Demos

We display demos of our plugins on our website to allow you to try them out in a limited capacity before deciding whether you’d like to purchase one.  As a result, our website makes requests to the servers of each of the associated social media networks in order to get the data to populate the feed(s) and to display images and videos. These requests make your IP address visible to that social media network, who may use it in accordance with their data privacy policies:

Facebook: <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/update>  
Instagram: <https://help.instagram.com/519522125107875>  
Twitter: <https://twitter.com/en/privacy#update>

The Tweets displayed in the Twitter feed demo include the ability to Reply, Share, or Like the Tweet directly on our website. If you choose to interact with these functions then you will make a connection to Twitter.com, who may collect your IP address, your web browser User Agent, store and retrieve cookies on your browser, embed additional tracking, and monitor your interaction with the widget, including correlating your Twitter account with whatever action you take within the widget (such as “liking” a Tweet), if you are logged in to Twitter. For more information about how this data may be used, please see Twitter’s data privacy policy: <https://twitter.com/en/privacy#update>

### Analytics

In order to provide you with both a better website experience and to help improve our products, we use analytics tools to collect basic usage data from our website visitors.  We use Google Analytics to collect general browsing information and data such as an IP address and location. The Google Analytics privacy policy can be found at the following link: <https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/dpa/dataprocessingamendment_20130906.html>.  When available, we also track the page history of visitors on our website to allow us to better understand how our website is being used. These tools may use cookies to help track website usage.

### Our Plugins

For GDPR information related to our plugins, please refer to [this page](https://smashballoon.com/gdpr-and-our-plugins/).

### Purchasing a Product

When you purchase a product on our website we collect personal data associated with the purchase and transaction, such as your name, email address, IP address, and billing address (if paying by credit card). We do not store your credit card information. This is processed by [Stripe](https://stripe.com/), who store the information securely on their encrypted servers ([privacy policy](https://stripe.com/us/privacy)).  The information listed above is sent to Stripe, who process the transaction and store the information securely.

When purchasing a product from us we will send transactional email related to your purchase, or attempted purchase. Example of these emails are: purchase confirmation receipt, account login information, checkout recovery email, license renewal reminder emails.

When logging into your account on our website, a cookie is set in your browser to allow you to remain logged into your account.

### Affiliates Program

If you sign up for our Affiliates Program, then we will also store the following information which you provide during sign up: name, email address, website URL, and payment email.

### Requesting Deletion of your Data

You can request deletion of your data at any time by contacting us [here](https://smashballoon.com/contact/).
